MAURO DI IANNI JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

London, UK

+44 7719529691

hello@mauromotion.com

mauromotion.com/portfolio

in linkedin.com/in/mauro-di-ianni

github.com/mauromotion

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+), ReactJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Responsive Design.

BACK-END

Python, Django, Flask, RESTful APIs, DjangoRestFramework.

DATABASE

SQL, SQLite.

DEVOPS & INFRASTRUCTURE

Linux systems administration, Bash scripting, Docker containerization, Self-hosting.

SECURITY & PRIVACY

Web application security fundamentals, Privacy-by-design principles, JWT authentication.

TOOLS

Git, (Neo)vim, npm, pip, bash, zsh, fish, Figma, Penpot.

ADDITIONAL

C programming fundamentals, Lua scripting, UI/UX principles, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere Pro), Maxon Cinema4D.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Strong visual design sensibility from Motion Graphics background.
- Effective client communication and expectation management.
- Problem-solving and critical thinking.
- Ability to quickly adapt to new technologies and workflows.

PROFILE

Detail-oriented Junior Web Developer with comprehensive full stack development training and valuable perspective from 10+ years in motion graphics. Combines technical programming skills with an eye for visual implementation honed through extensive digital media experience. Collaborative team player with proven experience working effectively in crossfunctional groups to deliver projects.

Focused on building responsive, functional web applications with clean, effective user interfaces. Advocate for open web standards, privacy-focused solutions, and accessible technology.

Seeking Junior Web Developer role to apply ReactJS and Django skills in creating accessible, privacy-focused web applications.

Eager to expand knowledge through learning new frameworks and programming languages.

CERTIFICATIONS

2024, November

- @ EdX Computer Science for Web Programming Professional Certificate.
- Marvard's CS50w Web Programming with Python and JavaScript Verified Certificate.

2023, September

@ Harvard's CS50x - Introduction to Computer Science - Verified Certificate.

2023, March

<u>FreeCodeCamp</u> - JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures - Developer Certificate

2021. May

@ School of Motion - Intro to Design Principles (Design Kickstart)

EDUCATION

2008

Laurea Triennale (Bachelor's Degree) in Arts & Cinema Studies.

Università degli Studi Roma Tre, Rome, Italy.

Final mark: 108/110 (equivalent to UK First Class Honours, BA (Hons)). UK ENIC Statement of Comparability: Level 6 (UK Bachelor's equivalent).

1998

Diploma di Esame di Stato (Maturità Scientifica).

Liceo Scientifico I. Vian, Bracciano RM, Italy.

UK ENIC Statement of Comparability: Level 3 (A Level equivalent).

INTERESTS & VALUES

- Open source software contribution and advocacy.
- Digital privacy and ethical technology implementation.
- Building inclusive and accessible web experiences.
- Creating self-hosted alternatives to proprietary solutions.
- Continuous learning in emerging web technologies.

LANGUAGES

Italian (native), English (advanced)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2018 - Present

Freelance Motion Designer - London, UK

Collaborations with various advertising companies and post production studios: Ogilvy UK, Byte, Adam&Eve, Coffee & TV, and others. For clients such as: Bitish Airways, American Express, Post Office, Specsavers, Ford, Sainsbury's, Spotify, etc.

2016 - 2018

Youview TV Ltd. - London, UK

Contractor Motion Designer working in the design team, producing UI/UX previsualisation prototypes, 3D asset, help videos.

2014 - 2016

Frame By Frame - Post Production Studio - Rome, Italy

Senior Motion Designer, animator, digital compositor.

Clients: RAI Radiotelevisione Italiana, Sky Italia, Leo Burnett, Saatchi & Saatchi, TBWA, Studio Universal, Dlvbbdo, Poste Italiane, Smart, AS Roma, Fremantle Media, Molinari.

2011 - 2014

Direct2Brain - Post Production Studio - Rome, Italy

Motion Designer, digital compositor.

Clients: RAI Radiotelevisione Italiana, Granarolo, Expo 2015, Moment, Yomo.

2009 - 2011

Euroscena S.p.a. - Post Production for Broadcast - Rome, Italy

Broadcast Motion Designer.

Clients: RAI Radiotelevisione Italiana,

Mediaset.

PROJECTS

Portfolio / Personal Website (Astro, vanilla CSS)

Designed and developed my portfolio/personal website using Astro and vanilla CSS.

Delish - Bookmarking app (Django, DRF, JWT auth, ReactJS, CSS modules)

- Designed and developed a Django and ReactJS application to save and organise bookmarks.
- Implemented a RESTful API with DjangoRestFramework plugin.
- Implemented a JWT authentication system with an http-only cookie and access token in memory only.

Self-hosted application suite (RaspberryPi, Docker, Tailscale)

- Deployed and maintained a personal suite of applications using Docker containers on a Raspberry Pi.
- Implemented a Tailscale VPN mesh network to access the services from the web.